<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://utf-x.sourceforge.net/xsl/utfxdoc_1_0/utfxdoc_xhtml.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE document [
    <!ENTITY utfx-version "0.0.9 alpha">
]>
<document xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://utf-x.sourceforge.net/xsd/utfxdoc_1_0/utfxdoc.xsd ../../lib/utfxdoc/utfxdoc.xsd"
 xmlns="http://utf-x.sourceforge.net/xsd/utfxdoc_1_0/utfxdoc.xsd"
 xmlns:utfx="http://utfx.org/test-definition">
    <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
    <title>Manual</title>
    <subtitle>Unit Testing Framework - XSLT</subtitle>
    <author>Jacek Radajewski</author>
    <author>Alexander Daniel</author>
    <version>Release &utfx-version;</version>
    <date>30 October 2006</date>
    <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
    <sect1 id="intro">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>What is 'unit testing'?</title>
            <para><link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unit_testing">Unit
                    testing</link> is a method of testing software modules such
                as functions or methods in isolation from other software
                modules. One or more unit tests is normally written for each
                software module. Each unit test only tests one unit of
                functionality. A collection of unit tests in a software project
                forms a <link
                    url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_testing"
                    >regression test</link>. Regression test when executed,
                automatically runs all unit tests and checks for regression in
                the software system. If all unit tests pass then the regression
                test also passes.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>What is UTF-X?</title>
            <para> UTF-X is an extension to the <link url="http://junit.org"
                    >JUnit</link> Java unit testing framework and provides
                functionality for unit testing XSLT stylesheets. UTF-X strongly
                supports the <link
                    url="http://xprogramming.com/xpmag/testFirstGuidelines.htm"
                    >test-first-design</link> principle with test rendition and
                test validation features allowing you to visually design your
                test before you start working on the on stylesheet. UTF-X was
                originally built to test XSLT stylesheet used in an XML
                publishing system so it has good support for DTD validation,
                XHTML and XSL:FO stylesheets. </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="quickstart">
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <title>Quick Start</title>
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <para>Currently this is the only 'getting up and running' documentation
            available. Future releases will ship with more detailed
            documentation.</para>
        <sect2>
            <title>Installing UTF-X</title>
            <ordered_list>
                <item>Ensure you have JDK 5.0 or higher installed on your
                    computer. UTF-X uses Java 5 language features and will not
                    compile or run on earlier version. You can download Java 5.0
                    software development kit either from <link
                        url="http://java.sun.com">Sun Microsystems</link> or
                    from <link
                        url="http://commerce.bea.com/products/weblogicjrockit/5.0/jr_50.jsp"
                        >BEA Systems</link>. </item>
                <item>If you are planning on compiling UTF-X or using the ant
                    build file (recommended) you will also need to have ant
                    1.6.x installed. You can obtain ant from <link
                        url="http://ant.apache.org"
                    >http://ant.apache.org</link>.</item>
                <item>Download the latest version of UTF-X from <link
                        url="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=110006"
                        >SourceForge</link>.</item>
                <item>Unzip the file in a suitable location.</item>
                <item>Run the samples by typing
                    <code><![CDATA[ant samples]]></code>.</item>
            </ordered_list>

        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
            <title>Creating Tests</title>
            <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
            <sect3>
                <title>Generating tests</title>
                <para>UTF-X ships with a test generator which can be used to
                    generate Test Definition Files (TDFs) from existing XSLT
                    stylesheets.</para>
                <para>
                    <class>utfx.testgen.TestGenerator</class> accepts a
                        <code>-xslt xslt_filename</code> argument which
                    specifies the path to the stylesheet from which we are
                    generating the test. The test file will be generated in a
                    directory called 'test' under the directory where the
                    stylesheet resides. If this directory does not exist then it
                    will be created. The TestGenerator will not overwrite
                    existing test files unless you pass <code>-f</code> as an
                    argument to the program. For example, to generate a TDF for
                    a stylesheet <code>c:\xsl\webpage.xsl</code> we would
                    execute:</para>
                <pre><![CDATA[java -cp build/jar/utfx.jar utfx.testgen.TestGenerator -xslt c:\xsl\webpage.xsl]]></pre>
                <para>which would create a directory <code>c:\xsl\test</code>
                    and a TDF <code>c:\xsl\test\webpage_test.xml</code></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Creating tests from scratch</title>
                <para>We suggest you look at the samples provided with the
                    distribution. You'll find these in the samples directory.
                    This manual has been created using one of those samples
                    (utfxdoc). As of UTF-X release 0.0.9 the UTF-X Doc sample is
                    shipped in its owned package and is available for download
                    from the same area as the UTF-X framework.</para>
                <para>See section <xref idref="tdf_structure"/>.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
            <title>Running Tests</title>
            <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
            <para>UTF-X currently does not provide any nice wrapper scripts or
                GUI front end applications which you can use to run the
                software. You have the following options: </para>
            <ordered_list>
                <item>run <class>utfx.runner.TestRunner</class> from the command
                    line ensuring that <code>utfx.jar</code> is in your
                    classpath. You will also need to pass in either
                        <code>utfx.test.dir</code> or
                    <code>utfx.test.file</code> property to the JVM and tell the
                    TestRunner that the test class is
                        <code>utfx.framework.XSLTRegressionTest</code>. So in
                    order to run UTF-X tests under <code>c:\myxslt_tests</code>
                    you would execute <code>java -cp build/jar/utfx.jar
                        -Dutfx.test.dir=c:\myxslt_tests utfx.runner.TestRunner
                        utfx.framework.XSLTRegressionTest</code></item>
                <item>Run UTF-X tests from an ant build file. See target
                    'samples' in <code>build.xml</code> in the project tree.</item>
                <item>Run UTF-X tests within your existing JUnit configuration.
                    Use <class>utfx.framework.XSLTRegressionTest</class> class
                    as the test suite. You will need to pass in either
                        <code>utfx.test.dir</code> or
                    <code>utfx.test.file</code> property to the JVM.</item>
            </ordered_list>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="features">
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <title>Features</title>
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <para> UTF-X &utfx-version; supports the following features:</para>
        <ordered_list>
            <item>XSLT transformation test case. This is achieved by passing the
                contents of the <code><![CDATA[<utfx:source>]]></code> fragment
                through the XSLT stylesheet that is being tested and asserting
                that the result is the same as the contents of the
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:expected>]]></code> fragment. Other
                types of assertions may be added in future releases.</item>
            <item>DTD that specifies the structure of Test Definition Files
                (TDFs). This feature allows for TDF validation and easy TDF
                authoring when using a DTD aware XML editor.</item>
            <item>
                <code>&lt;utfx:source&gt;</code> and
                    <code>&lt;utfx:expected&gt;</code> fragment
                validation using a DTD (no schema support yet). If the
                    <code>validate</code> attribute is set to <code>yes</code>
                on either of the two fragments then the framework will
                automatically create a corresponding validation test case and
                add it to the test file suite.</item>
            <item>TDF rendition (XHTML and XSL:FO). You can render test
                definition files to produce XHTML or XSL:FO output and therefore
                visually inspect your tests. This feature is particularly useful
                if you like the idea of test-first-design. It allows you to
                write all the tests before you start on the stylesheet.</item>
            <item>Automatic test file generation from existing XSLT stylesheets
                with <class>utfx.testgen.TestGenerator</class>
            </item>
            <item>Pluggable test file filters for locating test definition
                files. See the <code>utfx.testfile-filter.class</code> property
                in the <code>utfx.properties</code> file for examples.</item>
            <item>Pluggable parsers/pre-processors for
                    <code>&lt;utfx:source&gt;</code> fragment parsing
                    (<class>utfx.framework.SourceParser</class>). See the
                    <code>utfx.source-parser.class</code> property in the
                    <code>utfx.properties</code> file for examples.</item>
            <item>Pluggable result printers for formatting test results. UTF-X
                ships with a number of result printers including one for XML and
                one for ANSI colour terminals (e.g. Linux xterm). See the
                    <code>utfx.result-printer.class</code> and
                    <code>utfx.result-printer.output-file</code> properties in
                the <code>utfx.properties</code> file for examples.</item>
            <item>Absolute XPath expressions (e.g. <code>select="/tree"</code>)
                work as expected in the stylesheet under test. Additionally one
                can set the context node for a test with the
                <code>context-node</code> attribute in the
                <code>utfx:source</code> element. Note: context-node="/" can be
                used for named templates but not for match templates because it
                will recurse infinitly.</item>
            <item>Pluggable XSLT engines. This is achieved by setting standard
                JAXP <code>javax.xml.transform.TransformerFactory</code>
                property. UTF-X &utfx-version; has been tested with Saxon
                8.7 and Apache Xalan 2.6.0 Interpretive processor. JDK 5.0
                internal Xalan XSLTC and Apache Xalan 2.6.0 XSLTC have been
                tested as well and everything works fine but absolute XPath
                expressions because of <link
                    url="http://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/XALANJ-1928">Xalan
                    issue 1928</link>.</item>
            <item>UTF-X &utfx-version; has been tested on Windows XP, Linux
                and Mac OS X platforms.</item>
        </ordered_list>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="overview">
        <title>Overview of the Framework</title>
        <para>If you have read the previous sections then you now know how to
            get the software installed and what features it has to offer. This
            section attempts to give a detailed overview of the relationship
            between XSLT stylesheets and UTF-X Test Definition Files and the
            process of test driven XSLT development.</para>

        <sect2>
            <title>Address Book Sample</title>
            <para>The Address Book is a basic XML application that attempts to
                illustrate how the UTF-X framework works. You will find the
                Address Book sample in the <code>samples/address_book</code>
                directory under root of the UTF-X distribution.</para>
            <para>As the name sugggests, the Address Book sample is an XML
                application for storing contacts and their addresses. It
                consists of a Document Type Definition for validating and
                authoring the XML, sample XML document, XSLT stylesheets for
                generating HTML and XSL:FO, and UTF-X Test Definition
            Files.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Typical XSLT Development</title>
            <para>Now lets have a look at a typical XSLT development process
                using the Address Book as a concrete example. Starting off, we
                have the Address Book Document Type Definition file
                    (<code>address_book.dtd</code>). Not all XML applications
                have a DTD or XML Schema associated with them, but in this
                example we created one to enable XML content validation and ease
                of authoring when using DTD aware XML editor. The second file
                    (<code>address_book.xml</code>) is an example of actual
                Adress Book content. <code>address_book.xml</code> declares in
                its <code>DOCTYPE</code> that <code>address_book.dtd</code> is
                the DTD that defines the XML document structure.</para>
            <figure>
                <xml xml:space="preserve">
<address-book>
	<address-entry>
		<person>
			<first-name>Jacek</first-name>
			<middle-name>Wojciech</middle-name>
			<last-name>Radajewski</last-name>
		</person>
		<street-address>
			<street>Any St.</street>
			<city>Toowoomba</city>
			<state>QLD</state>
			<post-code>4350</post-code>
		</street-address>
		<home-telephone>
			<number>46589757</number>
		</home-telephone>
	</address-entry>
</address-book>
</xml>
                <caption>Address Book XML content.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <svg src="images/address_book.svg" height="400px" width="700px"/>
                <caption>Overview</caption>
            </figure>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="tdf_structure">
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <title>Test Definition File Structure</title>
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <para>This section looks at the structure of a UTF-X test definition
            file.</para>
        <sect2>
            <title>DOCTYPE</title>
            <para>DOCTYPE declarations are not required by the UTF-X framework,
                but are useful when a DTD aware editor is used to author the
                TDFs. DOCTYPE declaration can be either a simple reference to
                the UTF-X test DTD like this:</para>
            <pre><![CDATA[
<!DOCTYPE utfx:tests PUBLIC "-//UTF-X//DTD utfx-tests 1.0//EN" "utfx_tests.dtd">

                ]]></pre>
            <para>or a more complex one that also includes internal declarations
                with references to DTDs for the XML source and generated target:</para>
            <pre><![CDATA[
<!DOCTYPE utfx:tests PUBLIC "-//UTF-X//DTD utfx-tests 1.0//EN" "utfx_tests.dtd" [

<!ENTITY % utfxdoc PUBLIC "-//UTF-X//DTD utfxdoc 1.0//EN" "utfxdoc.dtd">
	%utfxdoc;
 
<!ENTITY % xhtml1_dtd PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN" "xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
    <!-- this must be commented out during test run; see issue 12 -->
    <!-- %xhtml1_dtd; -->
]>
                ]]></pre>
            <para> In the second case your XML editor will become aware of not
                only the structure of TDFs, but also the structure of your
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:source>]]></code> and
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:expected>]]></code> fragments.
                Authoring tests in this mode is much easier as the editor will
                ensure that both source and expected fragments are valid. Not
                all XML editors support internal declarations.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Stylesheet</title>
            <para>Immediately following the root element is a
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:stylesheet>]]></code> element which
                provides a pointer to the XSLT stylesheet that is being tested.
                UTF-X currently assumes that the stylesheet is in a directory
                above the one where the test resides. For example, if your TDF
                is located in directory <code>c:\myxsl\test\</code> and you
                specify that the stylesheet under test is
                    <code>my_stylesheet.xsl</code> then UTF-X will assume you
                are refering to <code>c:\myxsl\my_stylesheet.xsl</code>
                stylesheet.</para>
            <figure>
                <xml>
                    <utfx:stylesheet src="my_stylesheet.xsl"/>
                </xml>
                <caption>Specifying the stylesheet under test.</caption>
            </figure>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Source and expected validation</title>
            <para>If you want to enable source and expected fragment validation
                you must specify system and public identifiers. These
                identifiers are used to form the DOCTYPE declaration during the
                validation of each source and expected fragment.</para>
            <xml xml:space="preserve">
<utfx:source-validation>
  <utfx:dtd system="utfxdoc.dtd" public="-//UTF-X//DTD utfxdoc 1.0//EN"/>
</utfx:source-validation>

<utfx:expected-validation>
  <utfx:dtd system="xhtml1-transitional.dtd" public="-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"/>
</utfx:expected-validation>
            </xml>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>UTF-X test case</title>
            <para> Let us now look at the structure of an actual test case. Each
                test case must have a name followed by
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:assert-equals>]]></code>. Assert-equals
                has two required elements which are the
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:source>]]></code> and
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:expected>]]></code> fragments. </para>
            <figure>
                <xml xml:space="preserve">
<utfx:test>
  <utfx:name>sect1 with title only</utfx:name>
  <utfx:assert-equal>
    <utfx:source validate="yes">
      <section id="section1">
        <heading>Section 1</heading>
      </section>
    </utfx:source>
    <utfx:expected validate="yes">
      <a name="section1"/>
      <h1>Section 1</h1>
    </utfx:expected>
  </utfx:assert-equal>
</utfx:test>
                        </xml>
                <caption>UTF-X Test</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>UTF-X executes a test by passing the contents of
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:source>]]></code> through the XSLT
                stylesheet and comparing the result with the contents of
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:expected>]]></code>. If both are
                equivalent XML fragments then the test passes. Otherwise the
                test fails.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Passing parameters to named templates</title>
            <para> Parameters can be passed to named templates like in XSLT with
                the <code>utfx:with-param</code> element. </para>
            <figure>
                <xml xml:space="preserve">
<utfx:test>
    <utfx:name>named template with parameter</utfx:name>
    <utfx:call-template name="named-template-with-param">
        <utfx:with-param name="a" select="1"/>
    </utfx:call-template>
    <utfx:assert-equal>
        <utfx:source>
            <empty/>
        </utfx:source>
        <utfx:expected>
            <a>1</a>
        </utfx:expected>
    </utfx:assert-equal>
</utfx:test>
                </xml>
                <caption>UTF-X Test of named template with parameters</caption>
            </figure>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Stylesheet parameters</title>
            <para> With the <code>utfx:stylesheet-params</code> element,
                parameters can be passed to the stylesheet under test. It can
                also be used to define parameters in a stylesheet. This feature
                can be very useful for stylesheets which are normally imported
                by other stylesheets and which expect certain parameters or
                variables. These stylesheets won't compile unless we define the
                parameters in the TDF. </para>
            <figure>
                <xml xml:space="preserve">
<utfx:test>
    <utfx:name>stylesheet parameter test</utfx:name>
    <utfx:stylesheet-params>
        <utfx:with-param name="stylesheet-param1" select="'UTF-X'"/>      
    </utfx:stylesheet-params>
    <utfx:assert-equal>
        <utfx:source>
            <print-param1/>
        </utfx:source>
        <utfx:expected>
            <stylesheet-param1>UTF-X</stylesheet-param1>
        </utfx:expected>
    </utfx:assert-equal>
</utfx:test>                    
                </xml>
                <caption>UTF-X Test with stylesheet parameters</caption>
            </figure>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="limitations">
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <title>Limitations and Known Issues</title>
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <unordered_list>
            <item><code>&lt;xsl:template match="/"&gt;</code> can't be
                tested because UTF-X uses this matcher for the internal wrapper
                document when executing the tests.</item>
            <item>Absolute XPath expressions in the stylesheet under test don't
                work with JDK 5.0 internal Xalan XSLTC and Apache Xalan 2.6.0
                XSLTC because of <link
                    url="http://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/XALANJ-1928">Xalan
                    issue 1928</link>.</item>
            <item>For a full list of unresolved issues please check <link
                    url="https://utf-x.dev.java.net/servlets/ProjectIssues"
                    >UTF-X issue tracker.</link></item>
        </unordered_list>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="resources">
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <title>Resources</title>
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <unordered_list>
            <item><link url="http://junit.org">JUnit</link> is the core unit
                testing framework used by UTF-X. JUnit provides unit testing
                functionality for the Java programming language. </item>
            <item><link url="http://www.xsltunit.org">XSLTunit</link> is one of
                the first XSLT unit testing tools. Software development group at
                the USQ began the UTF-X project because they found XSLTunit too
                cumbersome to use. </item>
            <item><link url="http://juxy.tigris.org">Juxy</link> is another XSLT
                unit testing framework written in Java. </item>
            <item><link url="http://oxygenxml.com"><![CDATA[<oXygen/>]]></link>
                is an XML editor that supports internal declarations such as
                those used in UTF-X samples. All UTF-X XML documents and XSLT
                stylesheets have been authored using <![CDATA[<oXygen>]]> xml
                editor. </item>
        </unordered_list>
    </sect1>

    <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
    <glossary>
        <!-- ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ -->
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>Unit Test</term>
            <definition>A test which tests a single piece of functionality in a
                single software module. There is usually one or more unit tests
                for each software module (function, method or template). You
                will find a good explaination <link
                    url="http://www.extremeprogramming.org/rules/unittests.html"
                    >here</link>. </definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>Regression Test</term>
            <definition>An automated test consisting of many unit test.
                Regression tests are executed after changes to a software system
                have been bade to ensure that no regression (introduction of
                bugs or loss of functionality) has been made.</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>UTF-X</term>
            <definition>Unit Testing Framework - XSLT</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>XML</term>
            <definition>eXtensible Markup Language</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>XSL</term>
            <definition>eXtensible Stylesheet Language</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>XSLT</term>
            <definition><link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xslt">XSL
                    Transformations. XSLT</link> is a <link
                    url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming"
                    >functional language</link> designed to transform XML
                documents into other documents (most likely also XML). The most
                common use of XSLT is in transformation of XML documents into
                HTML or XHTML. </definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>XSL:FO</term>
            <definition><link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XSL-FO">XSL:
                    Formatting Objects</link> is an XML based <link
                    url="http://www.answers.com/topic/typesetting-language"
                    >typesetting language</link> specially designed to be used
                with XML and XSLT. XSL:FO is usually generated from an XML
                document by a means of a XSLT stylesheet and then processed
                through a XSL:FO processor to obtain a rendition, usually in the
                form of a PDF or PostScript document.</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>JAXP</term>
            <definition>
                <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JAXP">Java API for XML
                    Processing</link>
            </definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>DOM</term>
            <definition>
                <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document_Object_Model"
                    >Document Object Model</link>
            </definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>SAX</term>
            <definition>Simple API for XML processing</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>XSL:FO processor</term>
            <definition>or XSL:FO engine, is a software for transforming XSL:FO
                documents into human readable rendition, usually <link
                    url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Page_description_language"
                    >page description languages</link> such as PDF or
                PostScript.</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>Document Fragment</term>
            <definition>lightweight DOM Document. One of the most important
                differences between a Document and Document Fragment is that
                unlike a Document a Document Fragment does NOT have to be well
                formed in the sense that it does not need to have ONE root node.
                Good examples of Document Fragments are DOM representations of
                the contents of <code><![CDATA[<utfx:source>]]></code> and
                    <code><![CDATA[<utfx:expected>]]></code>
            elements.</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
        <glossary_entry>
            <term>TDF</term>
            <definition>Test Definition File. An XML file that defines a suite
                of UTF-X tests for a specified XSLT stylesheet.</definition>
        </glossary_entry>
    </glossary>
</document>
